Finding Aid for the Lois Crouch Papers, 1949-1988 LSC.1565
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lois Crouch papers
1949-1988
UCLA Library Special Collections
Crouch, Lois
LSC.1565
1 oversize_boxes (20 boxes (10 linear ft.))
Lois Crouch (1915- )was the director of the League of Women Voters of Los Angeles (1948-50), a member of the Commission for the Reorganization of Los Angeles City Government (1951-52), chairman of the sub-committee on citizens participation for the Citizens Urban Renewal Advisory Commission of Los Angeles (1957) and secretary of the advisory board for the UCLA YMCA (1956-58). The collection consists of papers relating to Crouch's involvement in the United Way (1979-87), the California Federation of Women's Clubs (1963-93), and the League of Women Voters and others.
Restrictions on Access
Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lois Crouch, 1988, 1993 and 1994.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9912181033606533
Biography
Crouch was born in Denver, Colorado, on February 13, 1915; BA (1936) and MA (1937), UCLA; director, League of Women Voters of Los Angeles, 1948-50; member of task force, Commission for the Reorganization of Los Angeles City Government, 1951-52; became chairman, sub-committee on citizens participation, Citizens Urban Renewal Advisory Commission of Los Angeles in 1957; secretary, advisory board, UCLA YMCA, 1956-58; member, Faculty Wives Club, UCLA.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of papers relating to Crouch's involvement in such organizations as the United Way (1979-87), California Federation of Women's Clubs (1963-93), League of Women Voters, and others. Includes minutes, reports, correspondence, and printed materials.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
United Way (Boxes 1-3,23,29).
Kellogg Fund (Box 3).
League of Women Voters (Box 4-9,11,24).
Personal (Boxes 10,17).
Pacific Palisades Women's Club (Box 11).
General Federation of Women's Clubs (Boxes 12-13,21-23,28).
California Federation of Women's Clubs (Boxes 14-23,25-27).
Miscellaneous (Boxes 20-21,27).
Epsilon Sigma Omicron (Box 21).
Citizens' Urban Renewal Committee (Boxes 21,24).
Redevelopment (Box 24).
Kellogg Foundation and United Way (Boxes 28-29).
Online resources.; Women civic leaders -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Women -- Societies and clubs -- Archives; California Federation of Women's Clubs; Crouch, Lois--Archives.; League of Women Voters of California; United Way of America.
- California Federation of Women's Clubs
  - District Bulletins
    - 1963-1967. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1968-1970. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1970-1973. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1974-1976. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1976-1978. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1978-1985. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1982-1984. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1985-1990. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - June 1989-September 1993. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Reports and workshops, 1970-1972. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - District president's reports, 1976-1978. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Marina District 1977-1978. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - District president questionaires, 1977-1978. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - State Board minutes correspondence, 1976-1977. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Activities--district and state, 1976-1978. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - State Board, May 1977-June 1978. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Leadership development material. (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
  - Marina district conventions, programs, The Call, 1981-1993. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Press chairman material. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - District Executive Committee Board and Council meetings, minutes, etc., June 25, 1976-May 1978. (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
  - Leadership development material. (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - State chairman's bulletin, 1972-1974. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - District deans of chairmen bulletin, 1972-1974. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Marina parliamentary study group. (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  - Federation kit, (?)., 1977/1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - District 18 Dean of chairmen report and material, 1972-1974. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Marina Satellites. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Procedures book, 1988-1990. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - District fashion show / fine arts festival programs, ca., 1967-1975. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - District lists of officers, 1976-1977. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Convention agendas for Executive committees, 1978. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Yearlings' calendar, 1967-1968. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - District mimeo material, 1966-1977. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - District material, 1972. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Marina district proposed budgets,, and, 1984/1985 1987/1988 1974/1975. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - District financial reports, 1970-1974. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - District financial reports, 1974-1978/1979. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - State chairman's bulletin, 1972-1974. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Mailing list--leadership development, 1972. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Installation guides, ca., 1968-1975. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Programs--district council, fine arts festival, fashion show, 1967-1972. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - District second vice president, 1972-1974. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - District first vice president, 1974-1976. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - State board meetings, 1972-1974. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - State board meetings, 1976-1978. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - District by-laws and warrants, 1982-1984. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Parliamentary law study club, and, 1894/1987 1990-1993. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - District philanthropy report, 1987-1989. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Appointment calendar, June 1976-May 1978. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - State convention speeches, 1978. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Leadership material, 1953, 1977. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - California Federation of Women's Clubs (CFWC) publications. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Marina District 18--annual convention programs, ca., 1968-1989. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Forms, questionaires, memos, ca., 1971-1974. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Leadership development, 1972-1973. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - P's and Cues, 1975-1976. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Marina District
    - 1969. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - 1970. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - 1971. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - 1973. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1974. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - 1975. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - 1976. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Parliamentary law study club year book, 1978-1979, 1979-1980, 1980-1981. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Parliamentary law study club year book, 1985-1986, 1986-1987. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Satellites yearbook, 1970-1980. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Marina chapter, 1972, 1977. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Pacific Palisades Woman's Club yearbook, 1966-1971. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Pacific Palisades Woman's Club yearbook, 1972-1978. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Frances Harriet Munger Club of Los Angeles, 1977-1978. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Los Angeles district--year book, 1955-1956. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - [No further description available]., 1993-1994. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Resolutions and procedures, 1972. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - [No further description available]., 1964-1966. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Procedures
    - 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - 1970-1972. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - 1972-1974. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - 1974-1976. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1972-1974. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Yearbooks
    - 1957-1958. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - 1958-1959. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - 1959-1960. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - 1960-1961. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - 1961-1962. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - 1962-1963. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - 1963-1964. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - 1964-1965. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - 1965-1966. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - 1966-1967. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - 1967-1971. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 1967-1968. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - 1970-1971. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - 1971-1972. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - 1972-1975. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 1972-1973. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - 1973-1974. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - 1974-1975. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - 1975-1976. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - 1978-1979. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - 1979-1980. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - 1978-1983. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 1982-1983. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - 1983-1984. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - 1986-1987. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Membership and Procedures
    - 1968-1969. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - 1969-1970. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Leadership development, 1968-1972. (Box 27, Folder 10)
- Citizens Urban Renewal Advisory Committee
  - 1960. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 1961. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 1962. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - 1963-1964. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - 1964-1965. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - University of Southern California master plan. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Temple urban renewal project, ca., 1960-1961. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - [No further description available]., 1957. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - [No further description available]., 1958-1965. (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Epsilon Sigma Omicron
  - Reading lists - thru Jan. '74. (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Kellogg Foundation
  - [No further description available]., 1981-1982. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Evaluation material,; meetings, 1983 1982-1983. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - [No further description available]., 1982-1984. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [No further description available]., 1984. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [No further description available]., 1985-1986. (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - [No further description available]., 1987. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Kellogg Foundation and United Way
  - Training Center
    - 1985-1986. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - 1987. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - 1988. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 1989. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - 1990. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - 1991. (Box 29, Folder 4)
- League of Women Voters
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - National voter, 1963-1993. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Los Angeles voter, 1965-1968. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles county voter, 1965-1969. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - California voter, 1958-1993. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of Los Angeles--The voter, 1992-1993. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Convention--state board minutes, May 19-22, 1952. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of California--convention, April 30-May 2, 1993. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of California--organization committee kit, October 18, 1951. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Legistlative action. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - League resource material on Los Angeles city government. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Card file (A - N)., 3 x 5 cards, in envelope. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Card file (Q - Z)., 3 x 5 cards, in envelope. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Calendar, 1952. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - State item / lit--section 1, League of Women Voters (LWV) kit., 1953-1954. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - State item / lit--section 2 (finance), November 1953. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ingelwood--correspondence & memos, 1953. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of California--convention (1954)-- correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Platform revision, 1953. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of California--miscellaneous material, 1953. (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Calendar, 1950. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous government publications. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Material on slum clearence from Housing Authority, etc. - planning for meeting pre West unit 1940. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Convention material, 1949-1953. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Annual reports, 1949-1950. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Convention material, 1949. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting--Los Angeles. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Board of directors--minutes--complete set--unit council annual meeting, 1951-1968. (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) county council. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - State board minutes--convention minutes--budgets, June 1950. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National voter--trends--action. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Social welfare. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Party responsibility and cross-filing. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cards--Valentine's & birthday. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Get well cards, 1967. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tickets. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--miscellaneous. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Personal. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Photos. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pocket guide to LA county, 1954. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Local current agenda (?)--personal. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of the U.S.--miscellaneous political material. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of Los Angeles county--county council, 1954. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - League of Women Voters (LWV) of the U.S.--21st national convention (Denver, Colorado), 1954. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Organizational materials. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - National platform--proposed revision, 1954. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - National League of Women Voters (LWV) material. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Voter's service. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Conservation, 1950-1952. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Finance--state government, 1952. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - National economic items, ca., 1941-1950. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Legislative activity, 1951-1953. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Legislative newsletter, 1951-1953. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Ballot measures, 1949-1952. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Planning, (publications)., 1949-1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Convention and other League of Women Voters (LWV) material., 1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Conservation, 1950-1952. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Finance--state government, 1952. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - National economic items, ca., 1941-1950. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Legislative activity, 1951-1953. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Legislative newsletter, 1951-1953. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Ballot measures, 1949-1952. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Planning, (publications)., 1949-1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Convention and other League of Women Voters (LWV) material., 1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 25 years of great ideas, 1946. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - [No further description available]., 1993-1994. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1992-1995 (Box 29, Folder 10)
- Other / Miscellaneous
  - O'Hair letter. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Energy publications. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous publications. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Order of the Eastern Star--Acacia Rose Croix. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Various club yearbooks, ca., 1974-1987. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Personal Items
  - Roberts rules of order (revised), Signed Winston Crouch., 1921. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Key to Dearborne, Michigan. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Heart-shaped candy box. Inscribed inside. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, clippings, publicity. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Awards, curriculum vitae, publicity, letters of thanks. (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Pacific Palisades Women's Club
  - Parliamentarian work, 1975. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Federation executive secretary, 1968-1970. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, October 1967-1979. (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Redevelopment
  - General plan for Little Tokyo, 1962. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Centroplis--The plan for central city Los Angeles, 1964. (Box 24, Folder 9)
- General Federation of Women's Club
  - Membership handbook, 1982. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Western States' Conferences, 1973 and 1974. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Adminstrative program book, 1988-1989. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Legislative material, 1975-1978. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Membership, 1973-1977. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Publications re membership, program planning, leadership, ca., 1966-1975. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Convention, 1976. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Publications. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - State Convention
    - 1968. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1970. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1971. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1972. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1973. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 1974. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1975. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 1976. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Conventions, 1972, 1974, 1976. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - National convention, 1974. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Conventions, 1973, 1977. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Publications. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Membership program, 1973-1974. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Membership material. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1966-1970. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Manual, 1978-1980. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Administrative program, 1980-1982. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Administration, 1971-1972. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Resolutions constitution & bylaws, 1969. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Program material, 1971-1972. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Program material, 1972-1974. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Program material, 1976-1978. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Phoenix, 1978. (Box 28, Folder 5)
- U.S. Marine Corps
  - How to respect and display our flag, 1974. (Box 27, Folder 9)
- United Way
  - Community Issues Council
    - 1983. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1983. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1985-1986. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Corporate Community Issues Council, 1982-1983. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Western Region--New Board orientation, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Western Region--Planning Council, 1979-1980. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Corporate Planning Council
    - Activities and meetings, 1980-1981. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Manual, 1979-1981. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - [No further description available]., 1979-1980. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - [No further description available]., 1981-1982. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Corporate Planning Council, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Community Issues Council, 1981-1984. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Western Region Planning Council
    - 1982. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1982-1983. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1982-1986. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1983. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1984-1985. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Western Region
    - Allocations, Volunteer Orientation Manual., 1982-1983. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Allocations, 1984-1985. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Allocations, 1985-1986. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Allocation Reports, 1985-1986. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Allocation Reports, 1986-1987. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - [No further description available]., 1986-1988. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 1978-1979. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - [No further description available]., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Planning council, 1983. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Strategic planning process, 1988. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Annual report, 1988-1989. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Executive summary, 1990. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Strategic implementation outline, 1990-1994. (Box 29, Folder 9)